我知道已经有段日子了
I know it's been a while.
老实说
I'm gonna be honest,
我忘了你
I forgot about you.
离开农场后  我们一直颠沛流离
After the farm, we were always moving.
但是发生了一些事
But something happened.
好事
Something good.
终于发生了
Finally.
我们找到了一座监狱
We found a prison.
爸爸觉得我们可以在这里安家
Daddy thinks that we can make it into a home.
他说我们可以在地里种庄稼
He says we can grow crops in the field,
找些猪和鸡
find pigs and chickens,
不再逃跑  不再外出觅食
stop running, stop scavenging.
洛莉快生了
Lori's baby is just about due.
那时她得在个安全的地方
She'll need a safe place when it comes.
对其余人来说
The rest of us,
安全已足够
we just need a safe place to be.
昨天我在自己的床上醒来
I woke up in my own bed yesterday.
属于我的房间里的属于我的床
My own bed in my own room.
但我一直留着背包
But I've been keeping my backpack.
枪不离身
Keeping my gun close.
我害怕在这里安家
I've been afraid to get my hopes up
只是个奢望
thinking we can actually stay here.
问题是  我担心自己
The thing is, I've been starting to get afraid
变成了惊弓之鸟
that it's easier just to be afraid.
但今早  爸爸说
But this morning Daddy said something.
如果你没有希望  那活着还有什么意义
If you don't have hope, what's the point of living?
所以我解开包  找出了你
So I unpacked my bag and I found you.
打算再用你记日记
So I'm gonna start writing in you again.
我现在这样写
And I'm gonna write this down now
是因为你得先写下愿望
because you should write down wishes
才能实现它们
to make them come true.
我们可以住在这里
We can live here.
我们可以在这里安度余生
We can live here for the rest of our lives.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译  冰蓝
翻译  蘑菇
翻译  Reginamoon
翻译  重案组李Sir
翻译  小饭
翻译  Marshal同学
翻译  鸟の森
翻译   CS小明漫画家
翻译/校对  送小孩  卫老哥
校对  Lemony  米小勒
时间轴  涛涛  森の鸟  雪贵人
特效  吉吉
后期  送小哥
总监  送小孩
行尸走肉
第四季  第十集
我们该做点什么
We should do something.
我们得做点什么
我们不是唯一的幸存者
We aren't the only survivors.
不可能
We can't be.
瑞克  米琼恩  他们可能还活着
Rick, Michonne, they could be out here.
玛姬和格伦可能逃出了A区
Maggie and Glenn could have made it out of A block.
有可能的
They could've.
你擅长追踪  你可以找到他们
You're a tracker. You can track.
走啊
Come on.
天快亮了  如果我们现在走  还能...
The sun will be up soon. If we head out now, we can...
好吧  你不去我自己去
Fine. If you won't track, I will.
可能是卢克的脚印  或者是莫莉的
Could be Luke's. Or Molly's.
不管是谁的  说明他们还活着
Whoever they are, it means they're alive.
不  这说明他们四五个小时之前活着
No. This means they were alive four or five hours ago.
他们还活着
They're alive.
他们从这里开始加速
They picked up the pace right here.
匆匆忙忙跑出来
Got out in a hurry.
情况变得不妙
Things went bad.
你有点信念会死吗
Wouldn't kill you to have a little faith.
是啊  信念  信念帮不了我们什么
Yeah, faith. Faith ain't done shit for us.
也没能帮上你父亲
Sure as hell didn't do nothing for your father.
我们找到他们时他们肯定很饿
They'll be hungry when we find them.
怎么了
What?
不是行尸的血
That ain't walker blood.
足迹一直往前
The trail keeps going.
他们打退了行尸
They fought them off.
不  到处都是行尸的足迹
No. Got walker tracks all up and down here.
至少有十几个
At least a dozen of them.
走吧
Come on.
我们不会死的
We're not gonna die.
谁也不会
None of us.
我现在相信了
I believe now.
为了我爸爸而相信
I believe for Daddy.
如果这也行不通
If this doesn't work,
我不知道如何坚持下去
I don't know how I could keep going.
别哭
Don't cry.
我想要卡萝尔
I want Carol.
她不在这儿
Well, she's not here.
给  别到腰带上
Here, put this on your belt.
天快黑了  我们要去哪
It's gonna get dark soon. Where are we going?
再走远点  跟上
Farther. Come on.
大家都死了吗
Is everybody dead?
它们会听到她的
They're gonna hear her.
我们不该待在这儿
We shouldn't be out here.
我们很快就会找到安全的地方
We'll find a safe place soon.
我们会的
We will.
给
Here.
有行尸
Walkers!
拿着  快点
Here, come on.
走吧  没事的
Let's go. It's okay.
我会给你找到吃的
I'll find you something to eat.
好了  走吧
All right, go.
看  葡萄
Look, grapes.
-可以吃吗  -可以  它们没毒
- Can we eat them?  - Yeah, they're good.
给你  丽兹  吃点吧
Here, Lizzie, have some.
好了  小宝贝
Come on, baby girl.
丽兹  递一张尿布给我
Lizzie, hand me a diaper.
好了  乖  马上就好
It's okay. All right.
再忍耐一下  朱迪思
Bear with me, Judith.
好了  不哭不哭
Okay, that's it. Okay.
它们会听到的
They're gonna hear her.
好了  乖
You're all right. Come on.
没事的  我知道
It's all right. I know. I know.
好了  你想要什么
All right, what do you want?
你想要什么
What do you want, hmm?
嘘  好了  乖
Shh. Shh. Okay, come on.
-它们来了  -我听到了  米卡
- They're coming! - Ah! I heard it, Mica!
不要吼她  她不了解行尸
Don't yell at her. She doesn't understand walkers.
你才不了解行尸
You're the one who doesn't understand them.
好了
Come on.
看好孩子
Watch the baby.
米卡
Mica!
-米卡  -她跑了
- Mica.  - She's gone.
你吼她  她才跑的
You yelled at her and now she's gone.
米卡
Mica!
Mica.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我害怕了
I got scared.
没事的  我们都会害怕
That's okay. We all get scared.
遇到危险就该跑
You did the right thing running.
-什么  -她做得没错
- What? - She did.
听到或看到行尸  应拔腿就跑
You hear or see a walker, you run.
不过  如果你在团队中
But when you're in a group,
要尽量和大家待在一起  好吗
you got to try to stay close to them, okay?
你流血了  我伤你很重吗
You're bleeding. Did I hurt your arm bad?
没事  比在监狱里时好多了
It was a lot worse at the prison. No big.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道自己做得不如丽兹好
I know I'm not like Lizzie.
不用道歉  你们都有自己的处事方式
Don't be sorry. You each do things your own way.
-但是你们都能做到  -就像你和萨沙
- But you both get it done. - Like you and Sasha?
你才不像萨沙
You're not like Sasha.
为什么
Why not?
因为你还活着
Because you're still here.
而萨沙不是
Sasha isn't.
你要干什么
Wh....What are you doing?
过来
Come on. Come on.
我要让你们眼观六路
I'm making sure you can see in both directions.
你们就这么小心待着
You stay like this and keep watch.
你要丢下我们吗
You're leaving us?
他们可能是监狱的人
They may be from the prison.
-我得帮他们  -我们需要你
- I need to help them. - We need you.
米卡  把你的衬衣塞到匕首后
Mica, tuck your shirt behind your knife
这样更容易拔
so it's easier to grab.
-我们没事的  -好
- We'll be okay. - Okay.
如果你们看到行尸要怎么办
What do you do when you see a walker?
-跑  -跑
- Run. - Run.
一起朝我这边跑  不到万不得已别开枪
Together, towards me. Only fire if you have to.
就在这里等着我回来  好吗
You stay right here until I get back, okay?
求求你不要走
Please, please don't go.
米卡  看着我
Mica, look at me.
你能应付的
You can handle this.
你很坚强
You're tough.
克里斯  往林子里跑
Chris, head for the woods.
不行
I can't.
乖  朱迪思  安静点
Come on, Judith. Be quiet.
她就是不停
She's not stopping.
拜托了  丽兹  想想办法
Please, Lizzie, do something.
它们会听到的
They're gonna hear us.
丽兹
Lizzie.
-爸爸  -克里斯多夫
- Ah! Dad! - Christopher!
- Dad! - Christopher!
丽兹  我们该跑了
Lizzie, we have to run.
丽兹
Lizzie?
Lizzie.
小心
Watch out!
泰尔西
Tyreese.
怎么会...
How... how...
你怎么找到我们的
How'd you find us?
你去哪儿了  你怎么...
Where were you? How'd you..
待在这儿  姑娘们
Stay here, girls.
沿着轨道走
Stay on the tracks.
是我的错
That was my mistake.
但是林子里更隐蔽
But the woods have more cover.
不  你不明白
No, you don't understand.
轨道那头有个地方
There's a place up the tracks.
那里很安全  你们可以把孩子们带去
It's safe. You can take the children there.
相信我
Trust me.
拜托了
Please.
沿着轨道走
Follow the tracks.
泰尔西
Tyreese.
我没跑
I didn't run.
我没有丢下丽兹
I didn't leave Lizzie.
看吧  坚强的小姑娘
See that? Tough little lady.
这里有水
There's some water in there.
-还有吃的  -好
- And some food. - Yeah.
给
Here you go.
我没看见你逃出去
I didn't see you get out.
我以为你
I thought you...
我当时不在里面
I wasn't there.
还没回去
I hadn't gotten back yet.
瑞克和我发现了一辆车
Rick and I found a car.
他把物资带回了监狱
He took what we had back to the prison
而我
while I...
继续寻找
kept looking.
你看见了吗
Did you see it?
只看到了结尾
I saw the end.
然后
And then...
我看见你跑进了树丛
I saw you running into the woods.
你离得太远了  我跟丢了  但是
You were far away. I lost you, but...
你找到了我们
You found us.
-我就知道你会找到  -是啊
- I knew you would. - Yeah.
也许我们可以绕回去  找到你的车
Hey, maybe we can circle back and find your car.
那些行尸  还有大火
The walkers and the fire...
你不能回那片墓地
you can't go back to a graveyard.
快看
Look.
避难所和社区  欢迎所有人
"Sanctuary for all. Community for all.
抵达就能活命
Those who arrive survive."
终点站
抱歉
Sorry.
你可以笑
You can smile.
你还活着  我理解
You're alive. I get it.
不是因为这个
That's not it.
好了
Okay.
泰尔西也许还活着  萨沙
Tyreese could have made it, Sasha.
我们不知道有没有人逃了出来
We don't know if anybody got out.
不
No.
我们知道
We do.
他怎么样
How's he doing?
不流血了
Bleeding stopped.
他会好的
He'll be all right.
我们背靠河流
Got the water to our backs.
岸边位置有利
Decent vantage points from the bank.
晚上就在这扎营吧
I'm thinking we camp here for the night.
很好
That's good.
你们在这应该很安全
You should both be safe here.
大巴开出去了  格伦也逃出来了
The bus got out. Glenn got out.
我要去找他
I'm gonna find him.
玛姬
Maggie.
如果一切顺利  大巴已经走远了
With any luck, the bus is gone.
它沿着主路向东走了
It was heading east down the main road.
如果我沿这个方向走
If I follow in that direction,
也许可以发现它的踪迹
I might be able to pick up its tracks.
你自己吗  就靠那把刀吗
Alone? With just that?
我没有弹药了  是的
I'm out of ammo, so, yeah.
我没找到贝丝
I couldn't find Beth.
我知道格伦逃出来了  也知道他的路线
I know Glenn got out and I know which way he went.
我要找到他  然后再回来找你们
I'm gonna go get him and I'm gonna come back for you.
-我们两个一起回来  -玛姬
- We both are. - Maggie.
我要去
I'm going.
我们不能分开  现在不能
We cannot split up. Not now.
我去了
I'm going.
你自己说的
You said it.
我们不能分开
We can't split up.
搭车者可能为逃犯
你可以帮我阻止她的
You could have helped me stop her.
如果你这是博我同情  不管用的
If you're trying to make me feel sorry for you, it's not working.
该死  那我不是白挨了一枪
Damn, it means I let myself get shot up for nothing.
我们找到他的可能性...
The odds of us finding him...
我们应该去找食物  住的地方
We should be out looking for food, shelter.
是吗  为什么
Yeah, why is that?
这样才能生存
So we can live.
然后呢
Then what?
什么
What?
也许我们的幸存意味着不能仅仅生存
Maybe we didn't survive just to keep surviving.
世事无常
Shit happens.
不是所有事情都有意义
Not everything has to mean something.
不是必须的  但是可以有
No, it doesn't have to, but it can.
你可以这样想
If you make it that way,
我们也是这样做的
and that's what it seems like we're doing.
这种活法我能接受
And I'm down with that.
玛姬
Maggie.
Maggie!
你们该走了
You should go.
玛姬  住手
Maggie, stop.
玛姬  玛姬
Maggie. Maggie.
我一定得弄清楚他在不在里面
I have to know if he's in there.
好吧
Fine,
但我们得一起干
but we do it together.
小心点
Smart.
每次放一个出来
We'll let them out one at a time.
我们得有两个人站在门边
Two of us should be at the door...
防止它们叠在一起顶开门
in case they stack up against it.
我必须站在这里
I have to be here.
我得看它们的脸
I need to see their faces.
我顶不住了
I can't hold it.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
但他们逃出来了啊
But they got away.
他们都是好人
They were good people.
全部都是
All of them.
你应该让我来
You should let me.
玛姬
Maggie?
Maggie!
子弹是满的
It's full.
你一枪都没开吗
Did you even fire a shot?
好吧  走吧
All right. Let's go.
走啊
Let's go.
你就打算待在这儿了吗
Are you just gonna stay here, huh?
你打算送死吗
You're just gonna die?
我和他们是一伙的
I was part of this.
我知道
I know.
那你这是做什么
So what are you doing?
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我们的子弹不多了
We're gonna run out of bullets.
拿着这个  还有这个
Take this and take this.
退开
Back up.
好了  我要你走在我前面  行吗
All right. I need you to stay ahead of me, okay?
我会掩护你  但我一个人做不到
All right. I'll cover you, but I can't do it alone.
准备好了吗
You ready?
走吧
Let's go.
快  走  走  走
Go. Go, go, go, go, go.
开枪  开枪  走吧
Shoot! Shoot! Come on!
你有没有看见我们的人逃出来
Did you see if any of my people got out?
我只见我姐姐出现在那片空地上
All I saw was my sister in that field.
她本不应该出现在那里
She wasn't supposed to be there.
她有枪  但它们向她涌了过去
She had a gun, but they just swarmed her.
她不该在那儿的
She wasn't supposed to be there.
我为他才这么做的  我信任他
I did it for him. I trusted him.
但他却杀了那个老人
And then he just killed that old man.
赫谢尔
Hershel?
他的名字是赫谢尔吗
Was his name Hershel?
对不起
I'm sorry.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
布莱恩跟我们说你们是坏人
Brian, that man, told us you were bad people.
我知道那不是真的
I know it's not true.
我能看出来
I can see it's not,
所以我们的所作所为  我的所作所为...
so what we did, what I did...
我太混账了
I mean, I'm a piece of shit.
你为什么还想要我帮忙
Why would you want my help?
我不是想要  我是需要
I don't want it, I need it.
我得找到玛姬
I have to find Maggie.
玛姬是谁
Who's Maggie?
我妻子
She's my wife.
你俩失散了吗
You guys got separated?
我当时在巴士上
I was on the bus and then
然后我下车去帮忙  她没看到我
I got off to help and she didn't see me.
你怎么知道她活下来了
How do you know if she made it?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是赫谢尔
But Hershel,
玛姬的父亲  是个伟大的人
Maggie's father, was a great man.
他跟我说过  只要有信念就行
And he told me all I had to do was believe,
而我正打算这么做
and that's what I'm gonna do.
咱俩都能活着是万幸
Neither one of us should be alive right now.
她逃出去了  所以你得帮我找到她
She got out, so you're gonna help me find her.
事情还没完
Things aren't over.
他们还没死
They're not over.
我也想这样相信
I want to believe that.
我也想
I want to.
你必须相信
You have to.
格伦  格伦
Glenn. Glenn.
格伦
Hey, Glenn.
希望你们看得开心  混蛋
Hope you enjoyed the show, assholes.
你有一条毒舌  知道吗
You got a damn mouth on you, you know that?
你还有什么
What else you got?